Finding Aid for Henry D. Brown papers, 1936-1960
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Henry D. Brown papers 1936-1960
Brown, Henry D., 1910-
1 linear foot
85956 Aa 2
Historian and manuscript curator; collected historical materials and various activities files.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Henry D. Brown and came to the library in several accessions (donor no. 1382 ).
No further to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Henry D. Brown was field representative at Michigan Historical Collections of the University of Michigan. He later became director of the Detroit Historical Museum.
The collection is divided into two series. The Collected and research materials series includes campaign materials collected relating to the 1936 Presidential election and research materials relating to the founding of the Republican Party. There is also miscellaneous relating to the life and career of William Henry Phelps and Henry D. Smith. The Personal and miscellaneous series consists of papers, 1937-1950, concerning the Ann Arbor Cooperative Society, correspondence with former members of Brown's Sunday School class serving in the armed forces during World War II, the outline of Michigan history course given by Lewis G. Vander Velde.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor Cooperative Society (Mich.); Brown, Henry D., 1910-; Depressions--1929--Michigan.; New Deal, 1933-1939--Michigan.; Phelps, William Henry, 1872-1939.; Presidents--United States--Election--1936.; Republican Party (Mich.); Smith, Henry D.; United States--Politics and government--1933-1945.; University of Michigan--Student notebooks.; Vander Velde, Lewis G. (Lewis George), 1890-1975.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Boy Scouts.; Brown, Henry D., 1910-; Children.; Military officers.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Collected and research materials
  - Campaign materials from the 1936 state and national elections, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Papers, undated, concerning voting behavior and the founding of the Republican Party, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Papers, 1939 and undated, concerning William Henry Phelps (Box 1)
  - Papers, 1888-1913 of Henry D. Smith (Box 1)
- Personal and miscellaneous
  - Papers, 1937-1950 concerning the Ann Arbor Cooperative Society, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1943-1946 with former members of Brown's Sunday School class serving in the armed forces, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Papers, undated, concerning the anti-slavery movement in Michigan and Professor Lewis G. Vander Velde's course in Michigan history (Box 2)
  - Miscellanea, 1936-1960 (Box 2)
  - Photographs: group portraits of Brown with an unidentified Boy Scout troop and with a group of naval officers (Box 2)